so let's look at the answer to our
simple implementation quiz
if we issue the next axis only when all
prior accesses are complete
what is the memory level parallelism we
get and the answer is the memory level
parallelism is exactly one
remember that memory level parallelism
is about
having a load
that misses
and gets sent to memory
and then
our processor continues finding
independent instructions here
in the hope of finding another load that
is a miss and sending it to memory while
the first miss is still going
what that does is that if we look at all
the misses in our program
we will do some execution
and then wait for memory to respond
and then do some execution and then wait
for memory to respond
then sometimes do very little execution
and wait for memory to respond
so basically our execution
with memory level parallelism of one
ends up being
the execution without the misses
plus
the time to access memory which is very
large times the number of misses we have
with memory level parallelism
we execute
we send the request to memory now we'll
wait for it
but meanwhile we execute a little bit
more and hopefully
find that next miss in which case we can
overlap misses and hopefully we will
find more than just two
so in this case
we have that the cost of each miss
in terms of memory access
was not paid every time
we paid really the cost of maybe
something like one and a half misses
total but we satisfied three misses here